因為我們正處於一個變化與挑戰的時期
For we meet in an hour of change and challenge,
希望與恐懼交織的年代
in a decade of hope and fear,
知識與愚昧並存的時代
in an age of both knowledge and ignorance.
我們獲得的知識越多，我們顯露出的無知也就越多
The greater our knowledge increases, the greater our ignorance unfolds.
因此毫不奇怪
So it is not surprising
有些人想我們再原地踏步多一會
that some would have us stay where we are a little longer
休息下, 等一等
To rest, to wait.
但是我們的休斯頓, 我們的德克薩斯
But this city of Houston, this state of Texas,
我們的合眾國
this country of the United States
不是由那些解甲歸田
was not built by those who waited and rested
只想回顧過去的人來建設的
and wished to look behind them.
我們決定登月
We choose to go to the moon.
我們決定在這個年代登月，以及成就其他
We choose to go to the moon in this decade and do the other things,
不是因為它們輕而易舉，而是因為它們困難重重
not because they are easy, but because they are hard.
通過這個演講, 約翰.f.肯尼迪把我們
With this one speech, John f. Kennedy escalated our cold war
和蘇聯的冷戰提升到了外太空
with the Soviet union to outer space.
現在, 如果我們不能在1969年前實現載人登月
Now, if we do not land a man on the moon by 1969,
我們就會讓肯尼迪無法兌現承諾
we will have broken JFK's promise.
而在世人的眼裏, 蘇聯將會贏得冷戰的勝利
And in the eyes of the world, the Soviet union will win the cold war.
更加糟糕的是
To make matters even more difficult,
中央情報局已經從一項太空計劃中
the CIA has discovered a leak
發現了一個漏洞
coming out of the space program.
絕密的美國研究出現在了蘇聯人的報告中
Top secret American research is showing up in Soviet briefings,
這意味著克格勃已經在NASA內部安插了鼴鼠
which means the KGB has implanted a mole inside NASA.
如果俄國人能夠竊取我們的技術, 他們就能在登月這事上擊敗我們
If the Russians are able to steal our technology, they could beat us to the moon.
就像他們在航天上擊敗我們那樣, 他們在1957後首先發射了伴侶號人造衛星
Just as they beat us into space with the sputnik satellite in 1957.
NASA局長, James Webb, 否認存在這個鼴鼠
The director of NASA, James Webb, denies the presence of this mole,
意味著中情局只能暗中安插一支隊伍
which means the CIA must move in a team undercover.
我們就是這麼進來的
That's where we come in.
請允許我介紹Owen Williams
Allow me to introduce Owen Williams,
和我自己, Matt Johnson
and myself, Matt Johnson.
我們通過光明招募計劃加入了中情局
We joined the CIA through the bright recruits program
從那時到現在都一直是同事
and have been working together ever since.
和我倆的攝制組一起, 我們組成了中情局的影視部
Along with our camera team, we make up the CIA's av department.
現在, 我們正在完成深紅行動
Currently, we are finishing operation deep red.
一項針對導演Stanley Kubrick(代表作《2001太空漫遊》)的調查
The probe into film director Stanley Kubrick.
但這項任務沒有讓我們充分發揮潛力
But this mission is not using us to our full potential.
我們正在申請調離深紅行動
We are asking to be transferred off of operation deep red,
調去拉鏈行動
and on to operation zipper.
進NASA去尋找那個鼴鼠
The mission into NASA to find the mole.
因為我們的攝影背景, 我們將會...
Because of our filmmaking background, we would make...
好, 停
Okay, stop.
停
Stop.
這是要幹啥?
What is this supposed to be?
嗯. 這個...這是個宣傳片
Okay. It's a...It's a pitch film.
它...這個...它是做給拉鏈行動的. 我想...
It... so... it's for operation zipper. I think...
拉鏈行動已經安排好了
Operation zipper's already been assigned.
我們知道
We know it has.
我覺得局裏搞錯了
I think the agency is making a mistake
派了個科學家去NASA
with sending a scientist into NASA.
嗯, 你的觀點沒個卵用
Well, your opinion means nothing.
是的, 好吧. 只是...只是...
Yeah, okay. Just... just...
如果你看完剩下的電影, 你會看到... 我已經看得夠多了
If you watch the rest of this film, you'll see... I've seen enough.
但是我們有個找出間諜的絕妙計劃. 我保證你
But we have an amazing plan for finding the spy. I'm sure you do.
Boles, 我們在這上頭很努力. 你真的不把剩下的看完?
Boles, we worked hard on this. You're seriously not going to watch the rest of this?
嗯. 我們能不能把這個拿給Brackett看?
No. Can we show it to Brackett?
不
No.
好吧
Okay.
這事有點冒險
This was a long shot.
我們入職才一年
We've only been here for one year.
以後我們會參加很多類似的行動
We'll get on missions like this in the future.
我覺得這會管用
I thought this was going to work.
你知道這並不是個難得的機會. 嗯, 你應該...
You knew that it wasn't a great chance. Yeah, you should...
Jared, 你怎麼還在拍
Jared, you should have cut when
你看見了, 這事不順
you saw it wasn't going good.
你本應該這麼來拍...
You're supposed to be filming so that...
我都沒注意到
I didn't even notice.
嗯. 嗨
Yeah. Hey.
好. 我有個主意
Okay, I got an idea.
我們派去的人, 應該看起來完全沒搞清狀況
We need to send someone who will look like they have no idea what's going on.
我們, 作為記錄片攝制組
Us, as a documentary film crew.
我們可以假裝我們來自國家教育...好, 我們得走了
We can pretend we are from the national education... Okay, we have to go.
我們走
We got to go.
這是不是個好主意?
Is this a good idea?
Andy? 它是個好...嗨, 它是個好主意
Andy? It's a good... Hey. It's a good idea.
你準備好了? 他們要是把我們開除了怎麼辦?
Are you ready? What if they fire us?
你第一句說啥?
What's your first line?
哦, 額, 你們的計劃是派遣... 好, 我沒事
Oh, uh, your plan is to send...Okay, I'm fine.
好. 走
Okay. Let's go.
人都到齊了?
Everyone here?
Boles...
繼續. 謝謝
Carry on. Thank you.
各位早上好
Good morning, everyone.
大家好, 我是特工Matt Johnson. 你們下面看到的是
Hello, my name is special agent Matt Johnson, and what you're about to watch
一部詳細闡述導演Stanley Kubrick和電影《奇愛博士》
is a film detailing the connections between Stanley Kubrick
之間關係的影片
and the film Dr. Strangelove or how I learned to stop worrying and love the bomb.
結論, Stanley Kubrick不是間諜
Conclusion, Stanley Kubrick is not a spy.
謝謝
Thank you.
有人提問嗎?
Are there any questions?
好的. 下一個是什麼?
That covers it. Uh, what's next?
事實上, Brackett總監, 對於下一個拉鏈行動的主要研究
Actually, director Brackett, I'd like to make a pitch for
我想做個保證
major research to be moved onto operation zipper next.
你們在搞什麼鬼?
What the hell are you doing?
你們想安排一個...
You guys are trying to put a...
外勤特工進入NASA. 裝扮成科學家, 然而...
Field agent inside NASA posing as a scientist, and...
Williams特工和我覺得這辦法行不通
Agent Williams and I don't think it will work.
這個鼴鼠, 如果存在的話,
This mole, if he's there,
可能從60年代初開始就已經在NASA了
could have been at NASA since the early 60s.
他一眼就能認出火箭科學家是我們的人假扮的
He's going to spot one of our guys pretending to be a rocket scientist instantly.
我們得派些人
We need to send people
看起來完全不知道發生了什麼事情
who are going to look like they have no idea what's going on.
我們
Us.
作為記錄片攝制組
As a documentary film crew.
我們可以假裝我們來自國家教育電視網
We can pretend that we're from the national education television network,
拍攝阿波羅記錄片
filming the definitive Apollo documentary.
我們去那記錄登月比賽. - 好主意
We're there to chart the race to the moon. Smart idea.
但蘇聯鼴鼠不會讓人公開拍攝他們
But no Soviet mole's gonna let anyone openly film 'em.
嗯, Brackett總監, 我們現在就正在窗戶外頭拍你
Well, director Brackett, we're filming you right now through the window.
不過你們得給我們買更好的攝像機
You're going to have to buy us better cameras, though.
老天爺
Jesus Christ.
拉鏈行動
國家教育電視台攝影: Andrew Appelle
國家教育電視台攝影: Jared Raab
國家教育電視台製片: Owen Williams
國家教育電視台導演: Matt Johnson
好, 我們走
Okay, here we go.
但願不會被他們識破
Let's hope they buy this.
好了?
Ready?
哇!
Whoa!
- Hi! Hi!
等我們拿下東西
Just let us get our stuff.
好, 好!
Yeah, yeah!
要幫忙嗎, 安迪?
You need help, Andy?
我們拍這個沒問題吧?
Do you mind if we film this?
嗯, 能有啥問題
Yeah, why not.
這邊, 大廳盡頭右轉...
Here, at the end of the hall on the right...
哦, 夥計
Oh, man.
這是任務控制室?
That's mission control?
嗯. 其實晚點我們會進去的
Yeah, actually. We'll have to get in there later.
嗯
Hmm.
Hi
Hi.
我們是記錄片攝像組
We're a documentary film crew.
Jared, 一定要拍到這個薯片, 別跑焦
Jared, make sure you're getting this crisp and in focus,
我可不想編輯跑焦的片子, 拜託
I don't want to have to edit together out of focus stuff, please.
- 抱歉. - 沒事
- Sorry. - No problem.
你們的辦公室就在這
Your office is just right here.
好了, 請進
Okay, here you go.
哇!
Wow!
你們還需要些啥?
You guys don't need anything else?
不用了. 要的話我們會來找你. 我們要先準備一下
No, uh, we'll come find you if we do. We'll just get set up.
謝謝Sharon
Thanks, Sharon.
再見!
Bye!
她沒看穿. 我們是記錄片攝像組
She bought it. We're a documentary film crew.
看見沒有他們怎麼看我們? 怎麼看攝像機?
You see how they look at us? See how they look in the cameras?
耶
Yeah.
這是我這輩子參加的最棒的任務
This is the best mission I've ever been on in my life.
這位是, 啊...這位是Matt
This is, uh...This is Matt.
Mike. 幸會
Mike. Nice to meet you.
額, 這位是Jared
And, uh, this is Jared.
他們在拍攝一部記錄片, 關於阿波羅任務
They're filming a documentary about the, uh... The Apollo mission.
哦, 好啊
Oh, okay!
那個, 基本上我們會問你做什麼, 以及...當然!
So, we basically are asking about what you do, and... Sure!
我準備好了. 好
And... and I'm ready. Yeah. Okay.
嗯, 我在這公共事務辦公室工作
Well, I work here in the public affairs office,
我的其中一項職責是
and one of my duties is
媒體產品, 特別是照片
the media products, specifically still photos.
我在舒格蘭的劇院裏站起來, 我說
And I stood up in the theater in sugar land and I said,
"別吃那些肉丸! 他沒洗過手."
"don't eat those meatballs! He did not wash his hands."
我必須...
I had to...
謝謝你的時間. 在我們登月之前回來看我們, 好不好?
I appreciate your time. Before we launch to the moon, come back and see us, okay?
我會的. 好.
I will. Okay.
謝謝. 這是個秘密. 我們知道了
Thanks, guys. That's a wrap. We got it.
好的. 記下來
All right, and mark it.
- 採訪Milt. - 第一遍
- Milt interview. - Take one.
謝謝你, Owen
Thanks, Owen.
好, 我想你首先可以告訴我們你的名字
So, I guess you can start just by telling us your name.
Milt Heflin.
你在NASA這裏做什麼?
And what is it you do here at NASA?
啊. 額...
Huh. Uh...
好
Okay.
把門關上
Shut the door.
各位, 我們能不能拍個休息室一片繁忙的鏡頭?
Guys, can we get a shot of just the lounge being busy?
我知道你們都正工作, 不過如果你們想...
I know you're all working, but if you want to just...
忙忙碌碌, 就像有什麼活動.
Busy, like there's some activity.
或者, 怎麼自然怎麼來
Or, do whatever feels natural.
好 開拍
And action.
不, 別看鏡頭. 坐好就行. 在那站著就行
No, don't look at the cameras. Just keep sitting. Just keep standing there.
佐藤榮作首相的部份東南亞...
Part of Sato's controversial south-east Asia...
北越人
the north Vietnamese
決定接受我們提供的...
decides to accept us offers...
蔓延600英尺成為一片巨大的火海
spread over 600 feet to become a gigantic pool of flames
一個叫做紫K的滅火器, 飛機上三次悲劇性的火災
a fire extinguisher called purple k, three tragic fires aboard aircraft...
稍等, Webb先生. 準備好沒有?
One second, Mr. Webb. We're good?
Webb先生, 告訴我, 他們說俄國人在太空競賽中領先
Mr. Webb, tell me, what does it mean
那是什麼意思?
when people say the Russians are ahead of us in the space race?
這個, 我覺得他的意思是
Well, I think it means that the job of
讓一些東西在沒有大氣層的
landing something on the moon
月球上著陸
where there's no atmosphere,
而且使用火箭來減速而不是加速
and using a rocket to slow it up,
而且還得讓設備正常工作
and having the equipment still work
這是件難度很大的事情
is a very difficult job.
額, 我覺得他的意思是俄國人也還在嘗試, 跟我們一樣...
Uh, I think it means the Russians are trying, just like we are...
這人的辦公室在哪?
Where's this guy's office?
但我覺得真正的意思是...
But I think the real meaning is...
再來兩片
Two more pieces.
-加油, Jared. - 好了, 好了!
- Come on, Jared. - Got it, got it!
好了, 等等
Okay, hold on.
我沒事, 開下燈
I'm fine, I need light.
好了?
Ready?
試音, 試音, 試音, 試音...
Test, test, test, test...
那你必須說清楚怎麼推進這事. 怎麼做
then you get to talk about how to go forward. To do it.
嗯, 我沒啥興趣
Uh, I am not much interested,
而且我認為討論技術交換這事不太現實
and I don't think it's very realistic to talk about technological interchange,
而且這種事情, 你首先得從最基礎開始做起
and this kind of thing. You first gotta get on the basis
就是...就是...
where... where...
好, 那個...
Okay, so...
他辦公室電話響的時候
His phone rings, in his office,
這個電話也會同時響
and this phone rings at the same time.
只要我們錄下來
As long as we're rolling
他一接電話, 我們就啥都有了
when he picks up, we get everything.
我找了個房子. 很漂亮, 紅色的
I found us a house. It's beautiful, it's red,
帶苗圃和院子. 你會喜歡的
it has a nursery and a yard. You'll love it.
床有多大?
How big is the bed?
是大床
It's a queen.
你現在是一個人嗎?
Are you alone right now?
不, 我在上班. 你在幹啥?
No, I'm at work. What are you doing?
想不想知道我穿的啥?
Do you want to know what I'm wearing?
Julie, 我現在沒空做這個. 我在辦公室
Julie, I can't do this right now. I'm at the office.
抱歉, 晚點吧
I'm sorry, maybe later.
嗯, 人家戴的是粉色文胸, 還有你買的黑色裙子
Well, I'm wearing a pink bra and that black skirt you bought me.
寶貝, Matt就在我旁邊. 我在上班. 我晚上打給你好不好?
Honey, Matt is right beside me and I'm at work. Can I call you tonight?
現在我把裙子脫了
I'm taking off the skirt now.
裏面啥也沒穿呢. 哇!
There's nothing underneath. Whoa!
你在幹嘛? 沒事
What are you doing? Nothing.
我想和你一起玩
I'm trying to have fun with you.
稍等, 等等...不!
Wait a second, hold on... No!
這是啥
What is it?
我們啥也沒幹. 我在上班
We're not doing anything. I'm doing work.
喂?
Hello?
不要啊
Don't do that.
你在電話裏找到啥?
What'd you find in that phone?
啥? 啥? 天吶
What? What? Oh, my god.
我們被竊聽了
We've been bugged.
我們被竊聽了, 各位. 我們被竊聽了
We've been bugged, guys. We've been bugged.
不, 不, 不!
No, no, no!
還有啥? 還是就這了? Owen?
Anything else, or is that it? Owen?
從車裏就搬這些了?
That's it from this car?
喂
Guys?
對不起了!
I said I was sorry!
你的帽子?
Your hat?
- 這還有幾個箱子. - 這都不是事兒
- A couple more boxes here. - These are not a big deal.
請不要碰我
Please don't touch me.
剩下的我來拿!
I'll get the rest!
我們都, 額, 已經碰到過, 還會繼續碰到緊急情況,
We both, uh, have had and will have emergencies,
而且, 嗯, 每一次飛行, 都存在極高風險的因素,
and, uh, that each flight, uh, has some element of extreme risk,
其中的部分因素...
and some elements of...
我代表我自己發表這個聲明, 是基於我的學識,
I made this statement on my own, from my knowledge,
嗯, 長期的學識...
uh, longstanding knowledge...
會讓我們推遲四年...
setting us back four years...
嗯...
Well...
啊...
Uh...
燃燒300秒降到月球表面
300 second burn to the lunar surface...
這啥也不是
This is nothing.
等會. 我們最多只能做到250秒?
Give it a second. 250 seconds is all we can do?
那是最大值
That's the maximum.
- 你知不知道... - 你有沒和TRW討論過?
- And you know that... - Did you talk to TRW?
-另一個聲音是誰? - 不知道
- Who's the other voice? - I dunno.
他們的燃料
Their fuels.
我們被Grumman坑死了
Grumman has fucked us.
他們做了個著不了陸的著陸器
They built a lander that can't land.
所以, 我們會拖後...
So, we are going back...
和誰?
With whom?
這會讓我們推後四年
This is setting us back four years.
嗯, 我同意. 這個必須得改.
Well, I agree. This is going to have to change.
改? 我們登不了月
Change? We can't land on the moon.
除非有奇跡讓Braun找到更輕的燃料
Unless by some miracle Braun finds lighter fuel,
否則五年內我們都沒法著陸
we aren't touching down for five years.
好吧...我們只會永遠在上頭繞著月亮轉
Okay... We're just going to be circling forever up there.
那我們跟所有人怎麼說?
So what are we telling everyone?
- 啥也不說. - 我們不告訴任何人...
- Nothing. - We don't tell anyone...
你聽懂沒有?
Do you understand what this means?
NASA做不到
NASA can't do it.
他們沒法送人上去再帶回來
They can't land man and come back.
你給Brackett打電話沒有?
Have you called Brackett?
當然沒有. 我得先告訴你們
Of course not! I needed to tell you guys first.
我們必須告訴Brackett. 我們必須現在就告訴Brackett.
We have to tell Brackett. We have to tell Brackett right away.
這事你得馬上報告. 我們需要幫助
This is something you report right away. We need help.
我們必須... 放鬆, 沒事. 嗯, 嗯
We have to... Relax, it's okay. Yes. Yes.
我們需要... 我會告訴你怎麼做的, 好嗎?
And we need... I'll tell you what to do, okay?
我會告訴你怎麼做
I'm gonna tell you what to do.
找出來電話上另外那個人是誰, 好嗎?
Find out who that other guy on the phone was, okay?
因為, 如果我們能在一個月內查出來,
Because, if we found this out in a month,
你TMD必須相信那個鼴鼠也能做到
you better fucking believe that the mole can do the same thing.
現在突然一下俄國人知道我們登不了月了
And now all of a sudden the Russians know we can't make it to the moon,
那TMD我們該怎麼做?
then what the fuck are we going to do?
好. 好. 好.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
你給蘭利(中情局總部所在地)打電話
You call Langley.
通了
It's ringing.
你覺得我會和總統通話? 不
You think I'll get to talk to the president? No.
這不是不現實
That's not unrealistic.
我可以. 他可能會, "我們必須馬上找總統"
I could. He could be like, "we need to get this right to the president."
我可能會, "好的, 頭,
I'll be like, "all right.
"告訴我他家電話. 我會..."
"Give me his home phone, sir. I'll..."
喂?
Hello?
Brackett總監, 這是Johnson特工從休斯頓打電話
Director Brackett, it's agent Johnson calling from Houston.
我們有重大新聞
We have big news.
是什麼?
What's that?
他們登不了月
They can't make it to the moon.
我們截聽到了一個電話
We intercepted a call
從James Webb (NASA局長)那
from James Webb.
就我所知, 他們能繞月飛行
From what I understand, they can circle the moon,
但他們沒辦法實際著陸
but they can't actually land.
他們...他們沒這個技術
They... they don't have the technology to do it.
他們說最快也要到1971年
They're saying 1971 at the earliest.
該死的
Damn it.
等我一會
Give me a minute.
好, 其他還有誰知道這事?
Okay, who else knows about this?
嗯, 沒人, 就...就...
Uh, nobody, from...From...
就我們所知
From what we can tell.
他們在電話上討論這事
They're talking about it on the phone
好像是個大秘密. 好像他們以前從沒討論過
like it was a big secret. Like they've never talked about it before.
嗯, 好
Okay, good.
另一個組要接管拉鏈行動
Another unit is going to take over zipper.
把你的隊伍撤出來
Get your team out of there.
啊...你覺得這有點, 啊
Uh... you think maybe that's a bit, uh,
有點短視嗎?
shortsighted in a way?
我們已經秘密在這了? 什麼...為什麼?
Seeing as we're here undercover now? What... why?
不要置疑我的命令, 小伙子
Don't question my orders, kid.
我沒有... 我不是要置疑. 我...
I'm not... I don't mean to question it. I...
我只是... 我只是覺得我們在這
I just... I simply think that we're here
而且我...我們必須想出該怎麼應對這事
and I... We have to figure out a response to this,
但是, 你要求我們...
somehow, and you've got us...
回家了我們
We're going home.
電影《月球旅行記》片段
導演喬治·梅裏愛1902年作品
被稱為「史上第一部科幻片」
只要我們倆有人在說話, 你就拍. 我不管你拍掉多少膠片
If either of us are talking, shoot. I don't care how much film you burn,
沒事, 知道不? 這會救我們的命
it doesn't matter. Okay? It's going to save us.
我們在這幹啥?
What are we doing in here?
坐下. 聽這個, 好吧
Sit down, just listen to this, okay?
那個...
Well...
等會...昨晚你有沒給Brackett打電話?
Hold on a sec... Did you call Brackett last night?
打了, 好沒有? 他怎麼說?
Yes, all right? What did he say?
好, 打開它
Okay, turn this on.
他們怎麼說?
What did they say?
我會告訴你他們說了啥的
I'm gonna tell you what they said.
好, 打開了
Okay, it's on.
嗯, 你聽到沒有?
Okay, you hear that?
嗯
Yeah.
- 聽出來沒有? - 嗯
- You recognize it? - Yeah.
是伴侶號(蘇聯發射的人類首顆人造衛星)
It's sputnik.
知道嗎? 你比我領先
You know what? You're ahead of me.
嗯, 是. 那是伴侶號
Okay, yeah. It's sputnik.
你怎麼知道它是伴侶號?
How do you know it's sputnik?
你能不能...你昨晚在這睡的?
Can you... did you sleep here last night?
它沒插入任何東西
That's not plugged into anything.
它...它只是在另一邊有個旋鈕. 它不是真的伴侶號
It's... it's just a dial on the other side. It's not actually sputnik.
它只是讓你以為它是
It's just making you think that it is.
它只是在隨機地嗶嗶響
It's just a random beeping.
因為你覺得那應該是伴侶號
And because you think that that's supposed to be sputnik,
所以你就相信它是伴侶號
that's why you believe it's sputnik.
登月我們就準備這麼干
This is what we are going to do with the moon.
我給Brackett打過電話了,
I called Brackett,
告訴他'69年他們登不了月
told him that they can't make it for '69.
你說, "好, 那, 你們必須想個解決辦法"
He said, "okay, well, you've got to figure out a way to fix it."
我說, "我們可以自己來
And I said, "we can do it on our own.
"我們可以拍個電影來表現我們在登月
"We can make a film that shows us going to the moon
"而不用真的登月"
"without actually doing it."
我們知道他們能飛去那
We know that they can make it up there.
我們不是...我們只在最後一段造假
We're not... we're faking the last little piece.
那一點點...一點點他們做不到的事情
The tiny... The tiny thing they can't do.
著陸和回來
Land and come back.
肯尼迪說我們要做的事情
The thing JFK said we'd do.
就只那一部份
That's the only part.
其他全部都是真的, 你明不明白?
Everything else is real, do you understand?
是的, 我懂你的意思
Yeah, I understand what you're saying.
我懂聽起來就像...
And I understand that it sounds like...
看這個, Brackett寄來的
Read this, it's from Brackett.
他寄了個報告? 是的
He sent a briefing? Yes.
如果我們能把這個拿開,
If we can pull this off,
我們就會看起來像天才一樣
we are going to look like geniuses.
NASA裏頭的四個人想出了怎麼
Four guys inside of NASA figure out how to
讓它看起來像是我們登了月. 我們成功了
make it look like we went to the moon. We did it.
太瘋狂了!
That's crazy!
我們一直在等的就是這個
This is exactly what we've been waiting for.
天上掉餡餅
It literally fell on our lap.
事成之後我們就能有自己的部門了
We could run our own department after something like this.
《雪崩行動》
翻譯: bob dong
還會不會有更多消息?
Is there more information coming?
關於什麼?
About what?
嗯, 目標和預算
Well, the objectives and the budget.
為什麼?
Why?
你不覺得它不完整麼?
This doesn't seem incomplete to you?
不完整? 怎麼? 什麼意思?
Incomplete? How? What do you mean?
嗯, 我...好...
Well, I...Okay...
知道不, 別...別擔心這個
You know what, don't... Don't worry about this.
他們顯然只告訴我們該我們知道的東西
They obviously told us exactly what they want us to hear,
所以我們的任務是拍一個測試, 就這樣
so our job is to film a test, and that's it.
走
Come on.
沒有...你心裏一點都不愧疚麼?
Does it... you don't have an ethical problem with this at all?
從哪方面?
In what way?
這是在撒謊
In that this is lying.
知道嗎, 這就跟那些善意的謊話一樣
You know what, this is like one of those good lies.
就像聖誕老人和復活節兔
Like Santa Claus and the Easter bunny.
好多小孩都瘋狂著迷
A lot of kids get really mad about those.
我們按每秒48幀來拍
So we're shooting this at 48 frames a second,
你要這麼來動...
so you're going to have to move like...
就像你被拎起來了...
Like you're being lifted up...
好嗎? 像這樣... 這東西有100斤重
Okay? Like this... This thing weighs about 100 pounds.
嗯, 就試試. 試試跳一下
Well, just try it. Try leaping a bit.
像這樣
Like this.
嗯, 好
Yeah, good.
走! 開拍! 開拍!
Go! Action! Action!
再多點
More that way.
再靠我一點
More towards me a bit.
往那邊走開
Walk off that way.
等會. 等會. 等會
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
停
Stop.
我們應該晚上拍
We should be doing this at night.
能不能, 能不能把燈往左邊移一點?
Can, can the light move a little bit to the left?
我被吞了 我在做飯
I'm being devoured and I'm cookin'.
不, 那太遠了. 那太遠了
No, that's too far. That's too far.
回來這邊. 回你右邊
Back over this way. Back to your right.
沒事...停!停!
It doesn't matter...Stop! Stop!
好, 現在往你左邊一點點
Okay, now a bit to your left.
燈光要往下多少?
How much does the light drop off?
你沒被蚊子咬死麼?
Are you not getting destroyed by mosquitoes?
嗯, 咬死了. 我要搞好這個. 稍等
Okay, I am, but I'm trying to get this right. Hold on.
畫面裏還有啥?
What else is in the frame?
額, 我看見後面有些木頭塊
Uh, I see some logs in the background.
是, 我也看見了. 好, 我去拿走
Yeah, I see it, too. Okay, I'm getting it.
你就是要...
That's what you're...
好了, 開拍吧. 沒事, 沒事
Please, let's just roll. It's fine, it's fine.
這不是木頭. 這是塊岩石
It's not a log, it's a rock!
沒事. 我們不把它拍進來
It's okay, we'll frame it out.
我要用它!
I'm going to use it!
我要把它拍進畫面裏頭
I'm going to put it in the frame.
你準備好沒有?
Are you ready?
開拍!
And action!
Owen, 跳起來
Owen, jump in the air.
老天爺
Holy shit.
開著的!
It's open!
嗨. 你來得正是時候
Hey. You're just in time.
坐. 那個...
Have a seat. So...
登月錄像...我先不說效果
The moon footage...I won't say how it looks.
我想你看看, 好不好? 關燈
I just want you to watch it, okay? Turn the lights off.
看起來可能有點不一樣
So it may seem a bit different.
我想你會喜歡的
I think you'll enjoy it.
那年我們還沒進局裏
This is the year before we got recruited.
哇
Wow.
哪位?
Who is it?
你好?
Hello?
Brackett總監, 這是個...額, 請進
Director Brackett, this is a... uh, come on in.
歡迎
Welcome.
見到你們真好. 這是個驚喜
It's great to see you guys. This is a surprise.
這到底是怎麼回事？
What the hell is going on?
你未經我授權就把項目方向給改了?
You're changing the direction on this project without my authorization?
好...閉嘴. 我還沒說完
Okay...Shut up. I'm not finished.
嗯, 我聽著...我把這個項目...
Okay, now listen...
I'm shutting this operation...
等等! 終止了. 結束了
Wait! Bring it down. It's over.
這是你捏造的?
You made this up?
嗯, 是的. 我捏造了個任務
Okay, yes. I made up a mission.
但那是因為在我提交給你之前, 我想確認它是可行的
But that's because I wanted to make sure it would work before I brought it to you.
我想我可能已經解決了
I think I may have solved
登月的問題
the moon problem.
只要...相信我. 看這個
Just... trust me. Watch this.
對不起
Sorry.
無視這個. 無視這個
Ignore this. Ignore this.
那些只是沙子
So that's just sand.
William穿著宇航服
William's in the suit.
我們用慢鏡頭來拍
We shot it in slow motion.
你明白嗎?
You understand?
我是說我們可以偽造登月, 這個不會很難
I'm saying we could fake the moon landing, and it wouldn't be hard.
所有人想看的
All people want to see
是電視上的一個畫面
is an image on a television screen
我們可以給到他們
and we can give them that.
火箭會升空
The rocket will go up,
我們會把錄像交給他們
we'll send our footage with them,
而宇航員們只需要把它發送回地球
and the astronauts will just beam it back to earth.
沒人會去想這是偽造的, 因為那得多瘋狂?
No one is going to think this is fake, because how insane would that be?
如果我們不出錯
And if we do it right,
他們就會一見就信
this is the kind of thing that sells itself.
Walter Cronkite 會給我們干一半的活
Walter Cronkite is going to do half the work for us.
讓我試試
Let me try.
你等一會
Give us a minute.
沒事
It's okay.
Hi
Hi.
哇!
Whoa!
好, 從下面那邊拍, 好不好?
Okay, just shoot from down there, okay?
Owen?
把...把你話筒戴上. 不
Put... put your mic on. No.
把你話筒戴上. 把你...只要兩秒. 把你話筒戴上
Put your mic on. Put your... It'll take two seconds. Put your mic on.
快. 只要兩秒. 我不戴, 好吧?
Come on. It'll take two seconds. I'm not doing this, okay?
滾開. 振作點!
Get the fuck off. Cheer up!
我們剛剛大獲提拔啊!
We just got a huge promotion, come on!
哇!
Whoo!
boles先生, 我猜我們又將會一起工作了
Mr. boles, I guess we'll be working together again.
歡迎來到德克薩斯
Welcome to Texas.
恭喜這個瘋狂的任務獲得了Brackett的批准
Congratulations on having Brackett approve this insane mission.
你們現在正在拍攝?
You guys are filming this right now?
是的, 我們什麼都拍. 這是部紀錄片
Yeah, we film everything. It's a documentary.
是部紀錄片
It's a documentary film.
好, 在我們啟動之前, 我知道技術上你是我上司
Okay, before we get started on this, I know you're technically my boss,
但我在推動這一切
but I'm running all this.
是
Yeah.
不. 我到這是因為你根本不知道你在幹嘛
No, I'm here because you have no idea what you're doing.
所以我說了算 你啥破事都不許推動
So I'm in charge and you don't run a goddamn thing.
所以別在我們背後搞搞震了, 行不?
So no more fucking around behind our backs, all right?
哇, 我聽說很糟糕
Wow, I heard it's pretty shitty.
Hi. 你怎麼樣?
Hi. How you doing?
國慶節快不快樂?
Enjoying the 4th of July?
嗯. 我心情大好
Yes, I'm in a great mood.
這對我來說也有點像個派對, 因為我們獲得提拔了
This is a bit of a party for me too, because we got a promotion.
是嗎? 嗯
Did you? Yeah.
誰告訴我這是怎麼回事?
Somebody just tell me what's wrong.
是不是...就是這個燒烤
Is that...That's the barbecue.
什麼燒烤? 燒烤時候出了啥事? 怎麼回事?
The barbecue what? What happened at the barbecue? What's going on?
看
Watch.
就在...
Right...
那裏. 看到沒有?
There. See that?
嗯, 兩個人. 嗯, 看這個
Yeah, two guys. Yeah. Look at this.
他舉著東西. 我們認為是超8攝像機
So he's holding something, we're thinking maybe super 8.
那可能是台35毫米照相機
It could be a 35mm still camera.
我們認不認識這人是誰? 他們可能是NASA的客人
And do we know who this is? Maybe they're NASA guests.
嗯, 我不知道. 遊客? 誰知道, 對不?
Yeah, I don't know. Tourists? Who knows, right?
可能沒啥
It could be nothing.
就是沒啥...
It is nothing...
哪位?
Who is it?
是boles
It's boles.
垃圾
This looks like shit.
一個人穿著宇航服
You have one guy in a space suit,
在沙地上跳來跳去...
prancing around on the sand...
還有塊石頭
with one rock.
你覺得誰會信這個?
Who do you think this is gonna convince?
我...Brackett信了
I...It convinced Brackett.
好, 現在你得讓我信
Well, now you have to convince me.
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
沒人會信這個
Nobody is going to buy this.
我以為你支持我做這個
I thought you were advocating for me to do this!
我原來在支持北木行動
I was advocating for operation Northwoods.
這個主意真是荒堂
I think this idea's ridiculous.
Mike, 你記不記得曾經提到過, 額, 測試地點
Mike, do you remember mentioning, uh, test locations
NASA用來做拍照的那個?
that NASA was using for photography?
能不能給我看看那些照片?
Would you mind showing me those pictures?
你是說在攝像機上, 還是...
You mean on camera, or...
如果你不介意的話. 我不介意
If you don't mind. I don't mind.
這些是地球上看起來像月球的地方?
These are places that look like the moon on earth?
正是. 這些叫做地質實地考察
Exactly. These are called geology field trips.
你是說月亮上的岩石
So you're saying that the rocks that are on the moon
和地球上的岩石完全一樣?
are the exact same as the rocks on earth?
我沒說完全. 我是說...但它們相似?
I'm not saying exact. I'm saying...But they're close?
它們相似到...到...
They're close enough that...That...
嗯, 我的意思是...如果你看到它們, 你會覺得, 額...
Yeah, I mean... So if you saw them, you would think that, uh...
哦對, 你可以在美國這的火山上
Oh, yeah, you can get an igneous rock
拿一塊火成岩
from a volcano here in America
然後告訴別人這是塊月球岩石
and tell somebody it's a moon rock
他們不會知道
and they wouldn't know.
真的? 嗯
Really? Yeah.
- 你好. -Owen在不在家?
- Hello. - Is Owen home?
他在車庫裏
He's in the garage.
你好棒
You look great.
FBI!
看這個!
Look at this!
地質學家在地球上有地方
The geologists have places on earth
已經看起來像月球
that already look like the moon.
這是巴林傑隕石坑, 大峽谷
This is the Barringer crater, the Grand Canyon.
我們拍了這個錄像
We shoot this test footage
然後和通過登月計劃得到的
and then compare it with the real moon footage
真的月球錄像做比較
that they're getting from the missions.
我剛剛搞明白!
I just figured this out!
嗯. 我出不了這趟差
Yeah, I can't go on this trip.
什麼? 什麼意思?
What? What do you mean?
為什麼?
Why?
因為...因為...我需要你
Because I... because I...I need you.
如果你不和我一起, 我就得一個人跟boles去
If you don't come with me I'm going with boles, by myself.
什麼? 你還在生我的氣?
What? Are you still mad at me?
對不起. 我沒有...
I'm sorry. I didn't...
Owen!
等等!
One second!
我...你必須原諒. 聽著
I... you have to forgive me for this. Listen.
我不能去
I can't go.
我被你害死了 我被...我被你害死了
You're fucking me. You are...You're fucking me.
這是個重大發射
This is the big shot.
土星五號運載火箭的不載人飛行
The ride without astronauts of the giant Saturn v live rocket.
阿波羅計劃. 這是阿波羅4號
Project Apollo. This is Apollo 4.
我們登月火箭的首次飛行測試
The test of our moon rocket in flight for the first time.
這是個開始, 一系列步驟中的第一步
It is the beginning, the first of many steps,
有一天會把人送上月球表面
which will someday put men on the surface of the moon.
你能看到多遠?
How far off can you see?
你必須拍成黑白的
You've got to picture it in black and white.
在這. 太陽在我們後面
With the sun behind us there.
我們甚至可以來個全景
We can even do a pan.
你覺得怎麼樣?
What do you think?
不知道你們是否能聽見, 女士們先生們
We don't know if you can hear, ladies and gentlemen.
飛船正在按計劃飛行...
But, oh, the flight is moving along as it should be...
750萬磅的推力
But our tape records are being thrown to the floor
在讓重型火箭不斷上升的同時,
by the roar of this mighty rocket,
巨大的轟鳴聲
as it continues to climb into the sky,
還把我們的攝像機都震到了地板上
on its seven and a half million pounds of thrust.
漂亮的場面, 難以置信的場面...
It's a beautiful sight, an unbelievable sight...
我沒告訴他這全是我偽造的
So I didn't tell him I made the whole thing up,
然後你和Brackett出現了
and then you and Brackett show up,
然後他給了我一拳
and then he punches me,
現在他表現得我們不是朋友了
now he's acting like we aren't friends.
你會怎麼做?
What would you do?
嗯, 我不會一上來就那麼做
Well, I wouldn't have done that in the first place.
對, 而是假裝你和我一樣愚蠢
Okay, yeah, but pretend that you're as stupid as me
而且你已經那麼做了
and you have done that.
該死的, 看這!
God damn it, look at this!
我們差太遠了
We weren't even close.
不開玩笑
No kidding.
這
Here.
好...好, 其他還有誰看過這錄像?
Okay... Okay, who else has seen this footage?
每個人
Everyone.
看, 這是我們想要的
See, this is what we need.
我們需要真的月球錄像
We need the actual footage of the moon.
我們怎麼把宇航員擺這前面做動作?
How do we get astronauts to act in front of this?
你可以先找個真正的導演
You could start by hiring a real director.
要不你就放棄這項任務
Or you could give up this mission.
對
Yeah.
嗨, 你好, don
Hey, don, how are you?
我是Matt Johnson
It's Matt Johnson.
不, 我是從休斯頓打電話
No, I'm calling from Houston,
他們派我到這進行拉鏈行動
they got me out here on operation zipper.
聽著, 能不能...我真的需要幫助
Listen, can...I actually need a favor.
我們知不知道Stanley Kubrick(《2001太空漫遊》的導演)的最後地址
Do we have a last known address for Stanley Kubrick
在我們執行深紅任務的時候
when we were doing operation deep red?
我在看他電影裏頭的一些效果, 然後...
I'm looking at some of his movie effects and...
"不, 我當然願意打招呼!"
"No, of course I'd like to say hello!"
"我當然願意打招呼!"
Of course I'd like to say hello.
我正在看東西
And I'm watching something.
你能不能告訴我?
Would you mind giving me that?
你好, 能不能給我一個紐約地址的電話號碼?
Hi, could you give me the phone number to an address in New York?
239.
額, 那是北極星產品公司
Uh, actually, it's Polaris productions, incorporated.
23...
我叫Matt Johnson
My name's Matt Johnson,
我是個紀錄片制做人, 在NASA工作
I'm a documentary filmmaker working at NASA,
我有幾個問題要問他
and I need to ask him a few questions.
他在那嗎?
Is he there?
是急事
It's an emergency.
當然不是. 不... 不是那樣的, 女士
Of course not. No. And... And that's not what this is, ma'am.
是, 你好, 我叫Michael Kubrick
Yes, hello, my name is Michael Kubrick.
我在找我兄弟
I'm looking for my brother.
這是美國長途
Well, I'm calling from the United States
我...我在嘗試聯繫他
and I'm... and I'm really trying to talk with him.
我們父親出事了
I've got some very bad news about our father.
能給我個電話號碼麼?
Can you give me a phone number for that?
英格蘭現在是幾點?
What time is it in England?
我在找一位Stanley Kubrick先生
I'm looking for a Mr. Stanley Kubrick.
我是來自美國的紀錄片製片人
I'm a documentary filmmaker from the United States.
這不是私人電話
This is not a personal call.
我是從NASA打的電話. 我在想是不是...
I'm actually calling from NASA and I'm wondering if...
哦, 謝謝
Oh, thank you.
你好, Madeleine. 我不太確信為什麼會和你扯到一起
Hello, Madeleine. I'm not sure why I got connected with you.
我從NASA打的電話
I'm calling from NASA.
我正在這拍阿波羅行動的記錄片
I'm making a documentary here about the Apollo program.
啊
Ah.
你們在那邊幹什麼,
What are you guys doing over there,
如果你不介意我問的話?
if you don't mind me asking?
Stanley Kubrick在拍一部關於登陸月球的新片
Stanley Kubrick is making a new movie about the moon landing,
我願意打賭我們可以使用那些
and I'm willing to bet that we can use the special effects
他在那邊用的特技來做這個
that he's doing there to do this.
好, 但是...
Okay, but...
我們不能不這麼跑去片場
We can't just walk onto a film set.
他有兩個NASA專家做指導
He has two NASA scientists advising him.
我們過去說我們想採訪他們
We're going to go and say we're going to interview them.
你看出來這是怎麼回事了嗎?
Do you see what's going on here?
Kubrick在讓NASA
Kubrick is getting NASA
確保他的太空電影看起來像真的太空
to make sure that his space movie looks like real space.
然後我們就用他的太空電影
And so we're going to use his space movie
來確保真的太空電影看起來像太空!
to make sure the real space movie looks like space!
你明不明白這得多瘋狂?
Do you understand how crazy that is?
歡迎來到英格蘭!
Welcome to England!
這還不大聲音?
It's not too loud?
不, 那個, 把它裝進一個袋子裏頭
No, well, it'll be packed inside the bag.
還行...用在現場, 只要能拍到東西
Not bad for... For on the spot, just figured it out!
Jared, 招手!
Jared, wave!
Jared, 招招手!
Jared, big wave!
對, 就是她
Yeah, that's her.
Madeleine!
你們不能帶攝像機進去
You won't be able to bring that camera inside.
恐怕你們一進去就得關掉它
You'll have to shut it off as soon as we get in, I'm afraid.
Kubrick...全部都是現場
Is Mr...The set's all live.
沒問題. Kubrick先生在不在裏面?
No problem. Is Mr. Kubrick inside?
他在. 但安保非常嚴密
He is, but security is very tight.
試圖靠近他的話你就會被扔出去. 所以不要
You'll be thrown off the set if you try to approach him, so please don't.
知道了. 請進
You got it. Go ahead.
謝謝
Thank you.
請在這等會
Please wait right here.
嗯, 好. 我們就待在這
Yeah, sure. We'll stay right here.
拍成中景可能更好
It might be better to just play it as a medium shot
- 在這種情況下 - 嗯, 嗯, 是
- in this situation. - Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
你能不能低著頭來做?
Can you do it with your head down?
在外面怎麼樣?
What about out there?
- 嗯, 不錯. - 就這麼干
- Well, that's not bad. - Let's do that.
對. 檢查一下大門, Doug
Right. Check the gate, Doug.
我...我一般絕不會做這個, 但這是為了個朋友
I... I would never normally do this, but it's for a friend.
他叫Matt Johnson. 嗯 嗯
His name is Matt Johnson. Mmm-hmm.
Jared, 告訴我你在拍這個
Jared, tell me you are getting this.
哦, 老天
Oh, my god.
抱歉?
Excuse me?
你怎麼弄出來的?
How did you set this up?
Owen, 那個叫前投影!
Owen, it's called front screen projection!
我們找到了!
We got it!
Kubrick的技術, 他怎麼假造...
Kubrick's technique, how he's faking...
我要...我要告訴你
I wanna...I wanna tell you.
Boles, 嗨
Boles, hey.
那個叫前投影
It's called front screen projection.
我們搞懂怎麼, 怎麼做了
We figured out how to, how to do it.
嗯, 好, 好的. 我會,
Yeah, okay, all right. I'll, uh...
你想我們直接飛去那, 還是...
Do you want us to fly right there, or...
當然
Sure.
好, 那個叫前投影
All right, it's called front screen projection.
Stanley Kubrick可以做出任何他想要的環境
Stanley Kubrick can fake any environment he wants,
只要把它投射到一面半透明的鏡子上
by projecting it through a semi-transparent mirror
再反射到一面巨大的銀幕上
and then onto a gigantic silver screen.
然後他透過那面半透明鏡子來拍下整個畫面
Then he films the entire scene through the same mirror,
攝像機和放映機成90度角
at a 90-degree angle to the projector.
最終效果就是出來的畫面
What it winds up doing is creating images
你分不清楚舞台在哪結束
where you can't tell where the stage stops
假造的照片背景從哪開始
and the fake photographic background begins.
你能在一個完全二維的空間環境裏頭
You have an infinite depth of field,
獲取無限的景深
into environments that exist completely in two-dimensional space.
我們可以用NASA在阿波羅計劃中拍到的
We can do the same thing with the lunar surface photography
月球表面照片來做同樣的事情
that NASA is taking on the Apollo missions.
電影特技可以非常逼真
Movie special effects can be very convincing,
特別是在你不知道你在看電影的時候
especially when you don't know you're watching a movie.
計劃是在德克薩斯租一個電影工作室
The plan is to rent a film studio in Texas,
雇一組人, 讓他們造一個我們自己的月球登陸器
hire a crew, and have them build our own lunar lander.
我們會把這個真實的道具
We'll mix this practical set piece,
和Kubrick的投影技術合成在一起, 然後, 變
with Kubrick's projection technique, and presto,
人正在月球上面行走
the illusion that man is walking on the moon.
現在我知道你可能在想這太暴露了
Now I know you're probably thinking this is too much exposure,
把外人牽扯進來的風險太高
and that the risk of bringing in outsiders is too high,
但是我們已經有極好的掩護
but we already have the perfect cover.
我們正在拍攝登月紀錄片
We're making a documentary about the moon landing.
說我們在搭建場景用於採訪, 這很正常
And it's not a stretch to say that we're building sets to conduct interviews,
拍攝備用錄像
shoot b-roll footage.
我們甚至可以說這是用來做模擬的
We could even say it's for simulations.
拜託, 絕大部份主流電視網絡已經在這麼做了
Hell, most of the major networks are doing this already.
唯一需要知道真相的人
The only people who need to know what's actually happening
是宇航員
are the astronauts,
你要選那些願意合作的
who you should select based on their willingness to cooperate,
然後James Webb
and James Webb,
他要麼只能跟我們一起干, 要麼閃開別擋道
who's either going to have to work with us, or get out of the way.
這塊是容易的
And that's the easy part.
我們還需要說服NASA的每一個人
We also need to convince everybody at NASA.
好消息是和火箭有接觸的人
The good news is the only people who are in contact with the rocket
全都在休斯頓的一間屋子
are all in one room in Houston,
在任務控制室裏
inside mission control.
如果我們能夠說服任務控制室
If we can convince mission control
他們做的都是真的
that what they're doing is real,
其他人都會跟進
everybody else will follow.
我們怎麼做得到?
How do we do that?
任務控制室監控著一切
Well, mission control actually monitors everything,
從宇航員的心率
from the heart rates of the astronauts,
到登月艙的確切位置
to the exact location of the lunar module
在降落月球過程中
as it descends to the moon.
他們通過無線電直接從飛船上
And they're getting all this information through radio,
獲得這些信息
directly from the ship.
好消息是在這項任務中
The good news is that they've run so many tests
他們已經做過這麼多測試
with this exact mission
他們真的獲得了成功登月的遙測數據
that they actually have telemetric data of successful lunar landings,
保存在阿波羅11號的導航系統裏
stored on guidance systems on Apollo 11.
這點上我們非常幸運
Here's where we get very lucky.
當指令艙運行到
As the command module passes along
月球背面的時候
to the dark side of the moon,
無線電信號無法穿過月球
the radio signals can't penetrate the core.
我們有30分鐘的窗口期
For 30 minutes, we have a window
宇航員用來從真實數據切換到假的遙測數據
for the astronauts to switch from real data, to fake telemetric data.
任務控制室會接收到
Mission control will be getting data
登月艙分離和在月球表面著陸的數據
of the lunar module undocking and landing on the lunar surface,
但完全是假造的
but it will be completely faked.
宇航員把那些數據
Combine that with our footage
和我們的錄像一起發送回地球
that the astronauts are going to pipe into the broadcast back to earth,
沒人會發現任何問題
and nobody's going to have any idea.
對NASA和全世界來說
As far as NASA and the rest of the world is concerned,
美國剛剛登陸月球
the United States just landed on the moon.
最後, 廣播
Finally, the broadcast.
因為需要慢動作, 我們不得不拍成電影
To shoot in slow motion, we have to shoot film.
廣播的話需要是視頻
To broadcast it needs to be video.
意味著我們不得不做個轉換
Which means we have to do a transfer,
這通常都沒有問題
which normally would be fine,
只是不能讓人們知道它原來是個電影
except that people cannot know it originally began as film.
這意味著有一點劃痕, 一點灰塵...
That means a single scratch, any dust...
好, 好. 我們知道了
Okay, okay. We got it.
謝謝你的演示
Thank you for the presentation.
你可以繼續
You can go ahead.
- 謝謝, 先生. - 和你的人講講北木計劃
- Thank you, sir. - Talk to your folks about the Northwoods plan.
告訴他們在上頭裝個把手
Tell them to put a hold on it
然後我們能知道進展
and we'll see how this develops.
總監, 北木計劃是什麼?
Director, what is the Northwoods plan?
我從來沒聽說過北木行動
I've never heard of operation Northwoods.
擊落阿波羅11號並歸咎於蘇聯
Shoot down Apollo 11 and blame the Soviets.
和飛船上的宇航員一起?
With the astronauts on the flight?
我們為什麼這麼做?
Why would we do that?
如果沒有你的電影
If your film doesn't come together,
那我們不得不做個後備計劃
then we have to have a backup plan.
我們的後備計劃就是那個
And that is our backup plan.
計劃? 我從沒聽說過北木計劃
Plan? I've never heard of operation Northwoods.
擊落阿波羅11號並歸咎於蘇聯
Shoot down Apollo 11 and blame the Soviets.
這些去月球的人是誰?
Who were these men going to the moon?
David Schoumacher介紹阿波羅11號乘員
David Schoumacher profiled the crew of Apollo 11.
Neil Armstrong
Neil Armstrong,
被選為第一個踏上月球
the man chosen to be first to step upon the moon.
每個人都說他聰明, 有禮
He is by all accounts intelligent, courteous,
冷靜, 家庭好男人
sober, a good family man.
他是這個角色的完美人選
He is perfect for the role,
好萊塢編劇都找不到這麼好的人
beyond what a Hollywood scriptwriter would dare.
Buzz Aldrin可能是這些宇航員中最聰明的
Buzz Aldrin is perhaps the most brilliant of the astronauts.
有人甚至說他是天才
Some say even a genius.
一篇軌道交匯的博士論文給他帶來的麻省理工的博士學位
His doctorate at Mit came after a thesis on orbital rendezvous,
和其他人一樣
and he understands the abstract theory of space mechanics
他懂得空間力學的抽像理論
as well as anyone.
在阿波羅11號的宇航員中Mike Collins看起來一點不像技術人員
Mike Collins is the least technical in outlook of the Apollo 11 astronauts,
反倒很像哲學家
but the most philosophical.
如果他不愛機器的話
If he does not love machines,
他確實喜歡紅酒, 書, 和玫瑰
he does love wine, and books, and roses.
一位認識三個宇航員多年的人說
A man who has known all three pilots for many years
如果他迫降在一個島上
says if he were forced down on an island,
他希望會是和Collins一起
he would want it to be with Collins
因為他的人格魅力
for the quality of his personality.
另一位說他希望是Aldrin
Another said he would prefer Aldrin,
因為憑著他的聰明才智
because with his intelligence
他很快就已經在把海水轉化成淡水了
he would soon be converting sea water to fresh water
然後有條理地解決問題
and otherwise logically attacking the problem.
但分析到最後兩人都同意
But both agreed in the final analysis,
他們希望是和Armstrong一起
that they would hope it was with Armstrong,
因為, 通過某種辦法, 他會帶他們脫離困境
because, somehow, he would get them off of it.
喂
Hello?
Boles, 我們剛回來. 你在哪?
Boles, we just got back. Where are you?
好. 把電視打開
Okay. Turn on the TV.
嗯, 好. 正在開
Yeah, okay. I'm turning it on now.
- 為什麼? - 小結下你剛才說的
- Why? - Summarize what you just said,
然後我們會問你幾個和見總統有關的問題?
and then we'll ask you some questions about seeing the president?
啊, 是的, 我想說, 在一年前
Uh, yes, I'd like to say that, uh, over a year ago,
約翰遜總統和我審查了太空計劃
president Johnson and I reviewed the space program
同意增加力量
and, uh, agreed to build strength
因此我可能在我62歲生日時退休
so that I might retire on my 62nd birthday,
剛好就是這下一個10月7日
which happens to be this next October 7th.
今天, 我們審查了我們的進度
Today, we have reviewed the progress we have made
總統已經同意
and the president has agreed
我可以在10月7日退休
that I could retire on October 7th,
到時候我62歲
when I will be 62.
我還想說另一件事...
I'd like to say one other thing...
嗯, 好. 我猜這意味著
Yeah, okay. Well, I guess that means
他不打算合作, 嗯?
he didn't want to cooperate, huh?
好, 是
Okay, yeah.
你回來後我會見你. 再見
I'll see you when you get back. Bye.
Andy!
對不起
Sorry.
你在做什麼? 給紀錄片拍東西
What are you doing? Shooting for the documentary.
哦, 好, 沒事
Oh, okay, fine.
Owen在哪? 他在醫院
Where's Owen? He's at the hospital.
什麼?
What?
Julie生了
Julie had the baby.
哦, 該死!
Oh, shit!
嗨
Hey.
我錯過了, 嗨?
I missed it, hey?
嗨, 媽媽
Hey, mom.
哇!
Wow!
Matt!
他叫什麼名字? Simon
What's his name? Simon.
我能抱抱他嗎? 當然, 如果你想的話
Can I hold him? Sure, if you want to.
我有話和你說. 我要和Matt談談
I need to talk to you. I need to talk to Matt.
好. 怎麼了?
Okay. What's up?
就一會
One minute.
好, 好
Okay, okay.
這是什麼鬼?
What the hell is this?
Jared給我看了那人的照片
Jared showed me the photos of the men
在燒烤時候看我們的那個人
who were watching us at the barbecue.
他們在拍我們, Matt! 好
They're filming us, Matt! Okay.
你把這些帶到醫院來幹啥?
Why are you bringing this up at the hospital?
放鬆!
Relax!
放鬆? 這可能是俄國人
Relax? This could be the Russians.
我們必須離開這個任務
We have to get off this mission.
如果我們被抓了, 中情局會拋棄我們, 好吧?
If we get caught, the CIA will abandon us, okay?
我要給Brackett打電話告訴他...不! 不! 不!
I'm calling Brackett to tell him...No! No! No!
你不能給Brackett打電話. 誰也不能打給Brackett
You are not calling Brackett. No one's calling Brackett.
你是在疑神疑鬼
You are being paranoid!
我希望是, 因為如果我是對的, 這就是那個鼴鼠...
I hope so, because if I'm right and this is the mole...
如果他們發現了我們在做什麼
If they find out what we are doing,
那我們就死定了
then we are fucking dead.
你明不明白?
You got that?
看起來很好
Looks pretty good.
"看起來很好"? 怎麼說話的, 夥計
"Looks pretty good"? Guys, come on.
你是不是在開玩笑? 好
Are you kidding me? All right.
這花了45000塊!
This cost $45,000!
真的? 是!
Really? Yeah!
哦, 老天, 別這個語氣
Oh, god, don't start that.
"真的? 嗨, 你被騙了
"Really? Hey, you got ripped off.
"嗨, 算了吧, 我能把這事做得...更省錢
"Hey, come on, I could have done this..." ...Cheaper.
"花20塊, 再加些體力活"
"with $20 and some elbow grease!"
說句"幹得好, Matt"你會死啊?
Do you think it would kill you to say, "good job, Matt"?
我是說真的. 你是不是覺得會死?
I mean that seriously. Do you think it would physically kill you?
嗯, 那是用來拍電影的
Okay, and it's for a film shoot.
我們在拍一部關於登月的紀錄片
Uh, we're making a documentary about the moon landing,
我們需要做一個月球表面
and we need to make a lunar surface.
相當於是個假的月球表面. 我們要的就是這個
And so it's like a fake lunar surface. That's what we need.
不知道你們能運多少沙子來給我們
So I don't know how much sand you can ship us.
不過, 四噸?
But, uh, four tons?
一車能裝多少噸? 能不能稍等?
How many tons are in a truck? Can you hold on a sec?
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
抱歉, 再說一遍?
Uh, sorry, say again?
其實, 我去過亞利桑那州一個叫煤渣湖的地方
Actually, I went to a place in Arizona called cinder lake,
那的沙顏色就像綜色的糖漿. 很漂亮
where the sand was brown as molasses. It was beautiful.
很漂亮的綜色. 融化的綜色
It was a beautiful brown. Molten brown.
他們上去後這些人會說點啥?
So, what are these guys gonna say when they're up here?
我們需要點他們能印成頭條的東西
We need something they can print as a headline.
敲點東西出來讓我們看看有啥, 好不好?
Type out a couple things and let's just see what we got, okay?
試試這個, "歡迎來到月亮"
So try this, "welcome to the moon."
接著!
Catch!
別管它, 就讓它在那, 那是我的岩石
So, no, leave that where it was, it's my a rock.
我想如果我們根本不說"美國"這個詞的話
I think if we never say the word "America."
是, 我們只是拿一個美國符號
Oh, yeah, we just take an American symbol.
就是. 老鷹
Exactly. Eagle.
- 自由. - 前沿
- Freedom. - Frontier.
前沿
Frontier.
那個需要在那邊做個坑
So that needs to make that pothole there.
那個上面有沒有標籤?
Does that have a label on it?
B. 那它就剛好在你腳那. 完美
B. So that goes right at your feet. Perfect.
我剛想出個點子
I just got an idea.
你覺得他們上到去後我們該讓他們做什麼?
You know what we've gotta have them do when they're up there?
是誰, 伽利略還是誰, 說過...
Who is it, Galileo or somebody, said...
扔羽毛
Oh, drop the feather.
扔羽毛和鎯頭
Drop the feather and the hammer.
他說, 在真空裏頭
And he said, in a vacuum,
鎯頭和羽毛會以相同速度落下
a hammer and a feather would fall at the same speed.
嗯, 好, 但我們該怎麼做出這效果?
Well, okay, but how are we gonna do that?
用鉛做的羽毛
A lead feather.
等等, 我們必須讓旗幟盡可能的穩定
Wait a minute, we gotta keep the flag as stable as possible,
因為旗子飄說明有風
because the wind resistance makes it billow.
你揮旗. 你不能揮!
You wave the flag. You can't do that!
好休斯頓, 我準備走出登月艙
Okay Houston, I'm about to step off the LM.
他在那留下了個腳印
He leaves a footprint there.
因為他們會在那留下腳印. 就是!
'Cause they would leave footprints there. Exactly!
我們可以把那些照片傳送回家
And we so can send photographs of that back home.
它是...那是...就是那個畫面!
It's... that's...That is the image!
寫下來! 腳印!
Write that down, the footprints!
"腳"這個字好噁心
The word "foot" is disgusting.
大家可能不想聽到"腳"
Maybe people don't want to hear "foot."
不, "隨著這一步." 你會說, "隨著這一步."
No, "with this step." You would say, "with this step."
"隨著這一步."
"With this step."
好, 好. "隨著這一步, 我..."
Okay, okay. "With this step, I..."
不. "當人走在月亮上的時候..."
No. "As man walks on the moon..."
太平淡了. 太平淡了!
Too literal. Too literal!
"一個人的這步..."
"The step of a single man..."
"一個人的這步."
"The step of a single man.
"但是對於後方在家s的我們來說..."
"But for us back at home..."
想想對我們來說一步像啥
Think of what a step is like to us.
對一個人來說, 一步就只是一步
To a man, a step is just a step.
但對一隻抬頭看人的螞蟻來說, 他看起來就跟神一樣
But to an ant looking up at the man, he looks like a god.
它看起來不像是一步
And it doesn't look like a step,
它看起來就像是巨大的飛躍
it looks like a towering leap.
像是躍進. 像是跳躍
It's like a leap. It's like a jump.
這個躍進是為了...為了一切!
And this is a leap forward for...For everything!
下一個進化步驟
The next evolutionary step.
科學上的躍進
A leap forward in science.
- 對人類. - 正是!
- For humanity. - Exactly!
這很好
This is good.
好, 我們試拍一個
Okay, let's try one.
嗨
Hey.
外面那人你認不認識? 誰?
Do you know who that is outside? Who?
就那
Right there.
看. 哪?
Look. Where?
告訴我他是誰
Tell me whose that is.
他在跑?
Is he running?
你有沒和他打招呼? 你進來的時候他有沒看你?
Did you say hi? Did he look at you when you came in?
裏頭究竟有人沒人?
Is there even a guy in there?
他一直坐在那看
He's sitting there watching.
噓. 噓. 走出去, 你就明白了
Shh. Shh. Go outside, you'll see.
我保證他是在這個製作室的員工. 我去和他聊聊
I'm sure he works for the studio. I'll go talk to him.
他們知道我們在這. 我們可以在這, 好吧?
They know we're here. We're allowed to be here, okay?
放鬆
Relax.
好
Okay.
嗨
Hi.
追, 追, 追, 追!
Go, go, go, go!
Jared, 上車!
Jared, get in the car!
Boles, 你在幹啥?
Boles, what are you doing?
怎麼回事? 你TMD開槍了!
What happened? You shot your fucking gun!
Jared, 拍前面
Jared, shoot out the front,
盡量拍到車牌!
try to get their license plate!
快!
Come on!
- 不! - 什麼?
- No! - What?
怎麼了?
What happened?
你的車怎麼了?
What happened to your car?
熄火了. 他們跑了
It stalled. They got away.
你有沒看見他們?
Well, did you get a look at them?
不管是誰, 他們知道我們在這
Whoever it is, they know we're here.
我們不知道他們是誰
Well, we don't know who it is.
我覺得是那個鼴鼠
I think it's the mole.
我覺得他就是你們當初把我們派來這找的那個鼴鼠
I think it's the mole that you guys sent us here to find in the first place.
等在工作室外頭那個是誰
Who else is waiting outside the studio
我們走出來的時候...讓我們把門鎖上
and then the minute we walk out...Let's lock it up.
鎖起來然後給Brackett打電話
Let's lock it up and call Brackett.
什麼...鎖起來? 我們才做了一半!
What... lock it up? We're in the middle of this!
我們不能停止拍攝!
We can't just stop shooting!
嗯, 屋頂上可能有人
Well, there might be guys on the roof.
什麼意思, 屋頂有人?
What do you mean, guys on the roof?
這TMD是怎麼回事?
What the fuck is going on?
什麼 你有槍?
And what, you got a gun?
這是CBS新聞特別報道
This is CBS news special report.
阿波羅8號飛船
The flight of Apollo 8.
六天時間來回月球
Six days to the moon and back.
Walter Cronkite為您報道
Brought to you by Walter Cronkite.
阿波羅8號的飛行已經結束
The flight of Apollo 8 is over.
剩下的只是把宇航員從太空艙中移出
And all that remains is to remove the astronauts from the space craft,
送到三公里外的
and carry them less than two miles
約克城號航空母艦的甲板上
to the deck of the carrier Yorktown.
太空任務的未來計劃, 當然
Future plans for space missions, of course,
已經顯著提速了
have been accelerated considerably.
意味著他們能夠
It means that they can keep to the hoped-for
在二月底或三月初
schedule of the next Apollo 9 mission,
按計劃執行阿波羅9號任務
late in February, or early in march,
以便測試登陸模塊
to test out the landing module,
然後直到載人登月
and, uh, then move on towards landing a man on the moon
七月中旬還有兩次飛行
two flights further on in the middle of July.
我們有一個消息和一個壞消息
So we've got good news and bad news.
好消息, 他的名字叫Antonin Lhotsky
Good news, his name is Antonin Lhotsky.
嗯. - 他是名克格勃特工
Uh-huh. - He's a KGB agent.
他就是那天晚上在工作室外頭那人
He's the man from outside the studio the other night.
哇, 什麼?
Whoa, what?
我們懷疑他一直就是那個鼴鼠
We suspect he's been the mole the entire time.
所以...所以他知道雪崩行動. 我們完蛋了!
So... so then he knows about avalanche. We're fucked!
我們覺得他並不知道
We don't think he does.
這幾天我們一直在審問他
We've been interrogating him for the past couple of days.
看起來他什麼都不知道
He doesn't seem to know anything.
我們突擊搜查了他的房子. 啥都沒有
We've raided his house. Nothing.
這人就是鼴鼠? 你們...你們抓到他了?
This guy's the mole? And you... you got him?
我們抓到他了
We got him.
然後怎麼? 我們才剛剛...
So, then what? We're just...
那我們沒事?
We're good?
嗯, 有一點
Well, not entirely.
我們, 額, 收到了新的情報, 蘇聯方面的進展
We, uh, got some new intel on the Soviet progress,
說明他們做得比我們原想的要好
and it turns out they're doing better than we thought.
看起來他們有可能在'69年底登月
It looks like they could possibly make it to the moon by the end of '69.
意味著我們最晚在四月份要全部做完
Which means that we need to be done by April at the latest.
這讓我們的時間非常緊迫
Yeah, that puts us on a pretty tight timeline.
他們知道我們在這
They know we're here.
我們可以在這, 好吧? 放鬆
We're allowed to be here, okay? Relax.
嗨
Hi.
追, 追, 追, 追!
Go, go, go, go!
Jared, 上車!
Jared, get in the car!
喂? Matt, 我們碰到麻煩了
Hello? Matt, we have a problem here.
有合同的人, 我不知道, 有的人
Gentleman got the contract with, I don't know, somebody.
這是他們說是鼴鼠的那個人
This is who they say the mole was.
我們採訪過他?
So we interviewed him?
是, 一年多前
Yeah, over a year ago.
記不記得你曾經讓我查過是誰給Webb打的電話?
Remember when you asked me to find out who was on the phone with Webb?
當然
Of course.
我記得
I did.
...秒降到月球表面
...second burn to the lunar surface.
然後我們可以進去...250
Then we can go in after...For 250.
我們只能做到250秒?
250 seconds is all we can do?
那是最大值. 你知不知道...
That's the maximum, and you know that...
你有沒和TRW討論過?
Did you talk to TRW?
是. 你知道他們的燃料的情況
Yeah. And you know how they are about their fuels.
所以我們有麻煩了...Grumman...
So we are in trouble...Grumman...
這什麼意思?
What does this mean?
所以鼴鼠知道我們登不了月
So the mole knew that we couldn't make it to the moon
一年多了?
for over a year?
我覺得不是
I don't think so.
我覺得Lhotsky不是那個鼴鼠
I don't think that Lhotsky's the mole,
我覺得工作室外頭那人不是Lhotsky
I don't think Lhotsky was outside the studio.
我的意思是, Lhotsky知道我們登不了月
I mean, Lhotsky knows that we can't make it to the moon,
所以也許他們...他不配合
so maybe they...He wouldn't cooperate
然後他們只好把他弄成替罪羊
and they had to make him a fall guy
說他就是那個鼴鼠
by saying that he's the mole.
他們?
They?
對
Yeah.
什麼意思? 中情局
What do you mean? The CIA.
好, 那麼, 在工作室外頭跟蹤我們的人是誰?
Okay, well then, who's outside the studio following us?
CIA特工
CIA agents.
所以boles沒對他們開槍
That's why boles didn't shoot them.
他們是一夥的
They're all working together.
他們全都在監視我們, 他們騙我們
They're all watching us, and they're lying to us.
為什麼? 有什麼目的?
For what? For what purpose?
我們做的一切他們全都知道
They know everything that we're doing.
為什麼...完全沒道理
Why... This doesn't make any sense.
他們沒理由跟蹤我們
There's no reason for them to be following us.
你...你有沒有...
You... have you...
以前你有沒有聽過陰謀論?
Have you heard of a conspiracy theory before?
有
Yeah.
我覺得我們現在就在裏頭
I think we're in one.
好, 伸腿!
Okay, leg out!
看起來不夠真實
That doesn't look real.
好, 知道我們該怎麼做嗎?
Okay, you know what we'll do?
數三下跳下來. 準備好了?
Jump on the count of three. Ready?
我會帶來反彈
I'm bringing the bounce in.
太高了
That's a big jump.
快, 你是Neil Armstrong
Come on, you're supposed to be Neil Armstrong.
他很勇敢. 準備好了?
He's brave. Ready?
開始
There we go.
額, 換個背景
Uh, change the background.
再換一個
One more.
這個怎麼樣?
How about that?
棒
Great.
很棒
That's great.
我們在他頭盔的反射裏頭拍到了啥?
What are we getting in the reflection of his helmet?
我在不在裏面?
Am I in it?
我們必須在後面替換掉
We'll have to replace that after.
看起來很棒. 你只要...
That looks great. And then you just...
我們必須按住這
We have to repress this.
放到動畫板上重拍
Put that on an animation stand and reshoot it.
這個是原版
This is the original from the sound stage.
然後加上環形山的紋理
And the crater textures are added after.
在工作室裏去除掉細節
Getting rid of the details in the studio.
你進去然後你用印刷油墨把這些區域塗黑
You go in and you black out the areas with litho ink.
讓我們把這個移下一點
Let's move this a little bit further down,
因為看起來有點太過直角了
because it seems a little too square.
和鏡頭成直角? 是
Square to camera? Yeah.
好
Sure.
哇
Wow.
好了? 很好. 好, 開始
Ready? That's good. Yeah, go.
成功了
It works.
Yes!
太神奇了! 再來一遍
This is amazing! Go again.
Matt. 嗯?
Matt. Yes?
看到這個沒有? 看到這個沒有?
Have you seen this? Have you seen this?
再來一遍! 再來一遍! Owen, 看, 看
Do it again! Do it again! Owen, look, look.
鎯頭, 羽毛
Hammer, feather.
落! 伽利略是對的
Drop! Galileo was right.
帥哥, 我在裏頭加在重量. 什麼?
Dude, I just put a weight in it. What?
"NASA科學家死了"
"NASA scientist dies."
今天早上的報紙
It's from this morning's paper.
搞啥...Matt, 是Lhotsky
Well, what the...Matt, it's Lhotsky.
什麼?
What?
Boles, 他肯定知道
Boles, he must've known about it.
聽著, 想想Lhotsky為什麼會死
Listen, think why Lhotsky's dead.
顯然, 是他在和Webb說話, 所以他們啥了他
Obviously, he was talking to Webb, so they killed him.
他們會殺了我...
They're going to kill me...
我們不知道那人為什麼死了. 不, 我們知道
We don't know why that guy's dead. Yes, we do.
他們會啥了我? 你在說什麼?
They're going to kill me? What are you talking about?
他們會把我們都殺了. 他們會殺了宇航員
They're going to kill us both, they're going to kill the astronauts.
我肯定...任何知道這事的人
I'm sure... Anyone who knows about this.
我肯定Lhotsky知道得太多了所以他們把他幹掉了. 就是這樣
I'm sure Lhotsky knew too much and so they got rid of him. Okay? That's it.
對! 對! 我說的就是這個!
Right! Right! That's what I'm talking about!
他就是那個鼴鼠, 好嗎?
He was the mole, okay?
不...他們在把東西串起來
No... no, they're tying off loose ends!
好, 那其他還有誰會死, 啊?
Yeah, and, so, who else is gonna die, huh?
他們會殺了Jim Webb? NASA的頭? 他也知道!
They're gonna kill Jim Webb? The head of NASA? He knows, too!
有可能. 有可能. 你不覺得他們會?
Maybe. Maybe. You don't think they would?
不! 好了, 穿上宇航服準備好, 行嗎? 閉嘴吧你
No! Okay, put the suit on and get ready, all right? Shut the fuck up.
有團東西在...在玻璃上. Owen, 你能擦掉嗎?
There's a glob of something on the...on the glass. Owen, could you get it?
不, 就在...你沒擦掉. 就在那兒
No, it's right... You didn't get it. It's right there.
就在, 就在那
Right, right there.
你...你在做什麼? 這只是個測試
What... What are you doing? It's just a test.
Boles, 我不接受你的命令!
Boles, I don't take orders from you!
- 哦, 真的? - 好了, 過來
- Oh, really? - Enough, come on.
是, 有人會讓我們被殺掉. 我不要接受他的命令
Yeah, I don't take orders from someone who's trying to get us killed.
Owen, Owen, Owen. 另扔了
Owen, Owen, Owen. Don't drop it.
他放他們走的. 不, 他沒有...
He let them get away. No, he didn't...
對不對? 他放他們走的!
Right? He let them get away!
你就是那麼做的. 哦, 真的?
That's what you did. Oh, really?
- 對, 你故意錯過的! - 嗨, 哇, 哇, 哇!
- Yes, you missed on purpose! - Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa!
你...你在幹什麼? 你在幹什麼? 我們是朋友
What... what are you doing? What are you doing? We're friends.
他們是誰? 我們是朋友
Who are they? We're friends.
他們是誰? 是不是Brackett? 中情局?
Who are they? Is it Brackett? The CIA?
為什麼你不告訴他你每天都怎麼在一直給Barckett打電話
Why don't you tell him about how you've been calling Brackett every day,
想讓Johnson總統扔掉這個任務. 告訴他!
trying to get Johnson thrown off the mission. Tell him that!
你在說什麼? 嗨, 問你的朋友
What are you talking about? Hey, ask your friend.
好, 等等
Okay, hold on.
告訴他. 告訴他
Tell him. Tell him.
我們決定登月
We choose to go to the moon.
我們決定在這個年代登月
We choose to go to the moon in this decade
以及成就其他
and do the other things.
不是因為它們輕而易舉，而是因為它們困難重重
Not because they are easy, but because they are hard.
因為這個目標能夠組織和檢驗
Because that goal will serve to organize and measure
我們最強的能量和技術
the best of our energies and skills.
因為這項挑戰我們願意接受
Because that challenge is one that we're willing to accept.
我們不願推後, 我們決戰決勝, 其他也是一樣
One we are unwilling to postpone, and one we intend to win, and the others, too.
我們將把火箭發射到
We shall send to the moon,
和休斯頓控制室相距38萬公里的月球上
240,000 miles away from the control station in Houston,
一枚巨型火箭
a giant rocket,
高度將近100米, 相當於這個橄欖球場的長度
more than 300 feet tall, the length of this football field,
採用新合金來製造, 其中有些還沒被開發出來
made of new metal alloys, some of which have not yet been invented,
能夠承受的溫度和壓力
capable of standing heat and stresses
數倍於現有材料
several times more than have ever been experienced,
這項任務前無古人
on an untried mission
這個天體並不熟知
to an unknown celestial body,
然後我們還要從那裏安全地返回地球
and then return it safely to earth,
以超過4萬公里的時速重回大氣層
re-entering the atmosphere at speeds of over 25,000 miles per hour,
要做到所有這一切...做到所有這一切而且準確無誤
and do all this... And do all this and do it right,
而且要第一個做到, 在這個年代結束之前
and do it first, before this decade is out,
我們必須勇敢無畏
then we must be bold.
所以, 在我們啟航的時候,
And therefore, as we set sail,
我們請求上帝保佑這個人類有史以來所進行的
we ask god's blessing on the most hazardous and dangerous
最艱難的, 最危險的, 也是最偉大的探險
and greatest adventure on which man has ever embarked.
謝謝
Thank you.
這是唯一的拷貝?
So this is the only copy?
是. 那, 現在怎樣? 我們就這麼拿去給Brackett?
Yeah. So, now what? We just bring it to Brackett?
哦, 我來拿給Brackett. 你留在這收拾乾淨
Oh, I'll take it to Brackett. You stay here and clean up.
收拾乾淨啥?
Clean up what?
收拾乾淨工作室. 銷毀全部東西
Clean up the studio. Destroy everything.
萬一我們...萬一我們還需要這些材料的話怎麼辦?
What if we... What if we need that stuff?
不會. 幹得不錯
We won't. Good work.
謝謝. 我會很快見你
Thanks. I'll see you soon.
- 嗨, boles. - Lhotsky不是那個鼴鼠, 對不對?
- Hey, boles. - Lhotsky wasn't the mole, was he?
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
是, 我不...
Yeah, I don't...
我不知道
I don't know.
我做這個太久了. 對不起
I've been working on this too long. I'm sorry.
嗯, 休息一下
Well, get some rest.
我會很快見你
I'll see you soon.
再見, 兄弟
Bye, buddy.
他一眼就能認出火箭科學家是我們的人假扮的
He's gonna spot one of our guys pretending to be a rocket scientist instantly.
我們得派些人看起來完全不知道發生了什麼事情
We need to send people who are gonna look like they have no idea what's going on.
他們登不了月
They can't make it to the moon.
我會告訴你他們說了啥的
I'm gonna tell you what they said.
心裏一點都不愧疚麼?
An ethical problem with this at all?
他放他們走的! 你就是那麼做的. 哦, 真的?
He let them get away! That's what you did. Oh, really?
對, 你故意錯過的!
Yes, you missed on purpose!
嗨, 哇, 哇, 哇! 你...你在幹什麼?
Hey whoa, whoa, whoa! What... what are you doing?
你在幹什麼? 我們是朋友
What are you doing? We're friends!
- 他們是誰? - 我們是朋友
- Who are they? - We're friends.
什麼, 你覺得那是你朋友? 誰, Brackett?
What, you think that's your friend? Who, Brackett?
中情局? 你為什麼不告訴他...
The CIA? Why don't you tell him about how...
嗨, Julie. 能把你丈夫借給我一下麼?
Hey, Julie. Can I borrow your husband?
他啥? Simon在睡覺. 在裏面
He what? Simon's asleep. Inside.
我可以去裏面, 你們好聊聊
I can go inside so you guys can talk.
你可以留在外面
You can stay outside.
不, 我不需要聊聊. 我想知道是不是...
No, I don't need to talk. I wanna know if, um...
你是不是打算...我們...我們去把那些材料從工作中去掉
If you wanna... we're... We're going to get rid of the stuff from work.
你想的話你可以去
You can go if you want.
不, 我要待在這
No, I'm going to stay here.
Simon怎麼樣? 這次的發射你們興不興奮?
How's Simon? Are you guys excited about the big launch?
好. 祝你們下午愉快
Okay. Have a good afternoon.
謝謝. 你也一樣. 我會很快再見你
Thanks. You, too. I'll see you soon, okay?
是. 再見
Yeah, bye.
早上好
Good morning.
距離發射還有1小時29分鐘53秒. 倒數正在進行
It's t-minus one hour, 29 minutes and 53 seconds and counting.
還有一個半小時, 如果一切順利的話, 阿波羅11號的宇航員
In just an hour and a half, if all goes well, Apollo eleven astronauts,
Armstrong, Aldrin 和 Collins
Armstrong, Aldrin and Collins
將從外面的39A平台發射升空
are to lift off from pad 39-a out there
踏上人類一直的夢想旅程
on the voyage man always has dreamed about.
他們的下一站, 月球
Next stop for them, the moon.
我們將親眼見證肯尼迪總統
And we are all about to witness the fulfillment
於1962年9月12日在德克薩斯州賴斯大學體育館
of that promise that president Kennedy made
許下的諾言變成現實
at rice university stadium in Texas, on September 12, 1962.
凌晨4點, 當我們到達一號門區域的時候
We passed 10,000 odd cars
那裏停泊的車輛有上萬台
parked around the gate-1 area at 4:00 A.M. when we got here.
車輛來自各個州份, 車裏的孩子們都瞪大了雙眼,
Cars from every state, with little kids staring wide-eyed,
我們看見年輕人們都手拿著望遠鏡
and we saw teenagers with telescopes.
對我來說這個場景非常感人, 因為
It was a very moving scene for me, because
美國人民以前關心, 我覺得, 現在也關心
Americans cared then, I think, and they care now.
沙地上寫著, "祝你好運, 阿波羅11號"
And it says, "good luck, Apollo 11" engraved in the sand.
這裏的倒數進行得非常順利
All going very smoothly here with the count.
倒數60秒
T-minus 60 seconds and counting.
我們已進入60秒倒計時. 電力傳輸已經完成
We've passed t-minus 60. Power transfer is complete.
12, 11, 10, 9...
Twelve, eleven, ten, nine...
點火序列啟動
Ignition sequence starts.
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
Six, five, four, three, two, one.
下午好. 這裏是美國廣播公司位於紐約的太空總部
And good afternoon from ABC space headquarters in New York.
和我在一起的是我們的科學編輯, Jules Bergman. 今天我們在直播間
With me is our science editor, Jules Bergman and we are on the air today
為您報道由阿波羅11號執行的
to bring you a complete report on some very, very important maneuvers
非常非常重要的行動
to be performed by Apollo 11.
基本上開始進行...
Basically a position to begin the process...
喂?
Hello?
Matt?
你在...你在不在看這個?
Are you... Are you seeing this right now?
- Matt, 他們沒死. - 中情局在騙我們
- Matt, they're not dead. - The CIA lied to us.
等等, 什麼?
Wait, what?
在工作室外頭跟蹤我們的那些人, 他們在我家外面
The men following us at the studio are outside my house.
你確信? 是, 我去你旅店
Are you sure? Yes, meet me at your motel.
搞什麼鬼?
What the hell?
Owen?
有人嗎?
Hello?
誰在那?
Who's there?
糟了
Oh, shit.
好, 好, 好
Okay, okay, okay.
啊...啊...
Uh... uh...
另一台車在哪? 另一台...
Where's the other car? Where's the...
後面外頭. 後面外頭
Um, um, out back. Out back.
好, 讓開
Okay, stand back.
對不起
Sorry.
今天有一種躁狂的熱情...
There is a delirium of enthusiasm today...
快接
Come on.
快接, 快接
Come on, come on.
快接, Owen. 快接!
Come on, Owen. Come on!
Matt!
什麼?
What?
那有台車!
There's a car!
Jared, 快跑!
Jared, run!
混蛋. 走走走
Shit. Go, go, go.
Andy, 抓穩
Andy, hold on.
操
Fuck.
他們就在後頭. 他們就在後頭
They're right behind us. They're right behind us.
拍他們的臉! 拍他們的臉! Andy! 拍他們的臉!
Get their faces! Get their faces, Andy! Get their faces!
TMD瘋了!
This is fucking crazy!
天吶! 老天!
Oh, god! Oh, Christ!
他有槍! 什麼?
He's got a gun! What?
- TMD有槍. - 快, 躲, 躲, 躲
- He's got a fucking gun. - Okay, duck, duck, duck!
混蛋
Shit.
怎麼回事
What's happening?
操, 操!
Oh, fuck. Fuck!
好了, 好了
Okay, okay.
離開這裏. 離開這裏.
Get out of here. Get out of here.
我在試. 離開這裏.
I'm trying. Get out of here.
老大, 他們就在我們前面
Dude, they're right in front of us.
是, 我知道
Yeah, I know.
他們想撞我們, 他們想撞我們!
They're gonna ram us, they're gonna ram us!
歐!
Oh!
Owen!
它們有的沒貼標籤, 是不是?
So they're not all labeled, right?
有'67, '68, '69. 但不是全部...不是全部都有標
It goes '67, '68, '69. But not everything's... Not everything's marked.
你會找出來的
Well, you'll figure it out.
嗨
Hey.
好的
Okay, man.
我一知道我們去哪, 我就給你電話
As soon as I know where we're going, I'll call you.
好
Yeah.
晚上好
Good evening.
你好, 酒吧盡頭有個戴眼鏡的男的
Hello, there's a man at the end of the bar wearing glasses.
能不能叫他來聽電話?
Could you please give the phone to him?
您的電話
Telephone.
喂?
Hello?
你真的是個垃圾, 你知不知道?
You're a real piece of shit, you know that?
我們一直在找你. 你去哪了?
We're looking for you. Where you been?
我來告訴你. 我們來做的交易
Yeah, I'll tell you what, let's make a trade.
好
Okay.
在你要暗殺的特工名單上我的位置
My location for the names of the agents on your kill team.
我們沒有什麼暗殺名單
We don't have any kill team.
好, 那是誰殺的Owen把他吊死在車庫裏頭?
Yeah, well, who killed Owen and hung him in his garage?
好. 下來辦公室. 我們需要談談
Okay. Come down to the office. We'll discuss it.
好. 我會進來.
Yeah, I'll come in.
不, 我來告訴你會發生什麼事
No, I'll tell you what's gonna happen.
我把我們做的一切全都拍下來了
I have a film of everything we did.
我有中情局密謀假造登月的證據
I have proof that the CIA conspired to fake the moon landing
Owen Williams就是那個每個人都將看到的在月亮上行走的人
and that Owen Williams is the one that everybody is about to see walk on the moon.
你為了保密就把他殺了
And that you killed him to keep it a secret.
我還有拍到你計劃北木行動
I even got you planning Northwoods,
就跟我現在有拍到你一樣
the same as I got you right now.
沒人會把這個當真的, 小朋友
No one will take that seriously, kid.
好, 說我信口胡扯
Yeah, well, call my bluff.
我最後的影片會讓世人相信我們去了月亮
My last movie's about to convince the world we went to the moon.
那為什麼我不和你做個交易?
Then why don't I make you a deal?
回來為我們干
Come back and work for us,
我會讓你當你自己部門的頭
and I'll make you the head of your own department.
你以為我是有多愚蠢?
Yeah, how stupid do you think I am?
我來告訴你
I'll tell you what.
把影片作為要挾, 如果你不信我的話. 還是想想我的提議
Keep the film as collateral if you don't believe me. Just think about it.
逐漸靠近的時候
The surface appears to be, uh,
表面顯得非常非常細膩
very, very fine grained as you get close to it.
幾乎就跟粉末一樣
It's almost like a powder.
下面, 嗯, 非常細膩
Down there, uh, is very fine.
好, 現在我準備走出登月艙
Okay, I'm going to step off the LM now.
對一個人來說是一小步,
That's one small step for man,
對人類而言是一大步
one giant leap for mankind.
表面很精細, 全是粉塵
And the, uh, the surface is fine and powdery.
我可以...我可以用腳趾把它鬆散地撿起來
I can... I can pick it up loosely with my toe.
它們堆成...
It does adhere in fine...
好, 在地球升起來之前
Okay, we shouldn't take
我們不能用這卷再拍更多照片了, 我覺得
any more pictures on this roll until earth comes, I don't think.
快用完了. 快用完了, 我們還剩最後一個彩色膠卷
This is about out, it's just about out until our last color roll,
我們一回到地球就得換成黑白膠捲了
so, uh, we'll switch to black and white as soon as we get to earth.
- 我們可能來得及. - 是
- We might make it in time. - Yeah.
在那, 升起來了. 什麼?
There it is, it's coming up. What?
地球. 看見沒有?
The earth. You see it?
是
Yeah.
真漂亮. 升起來一半
Beautiful. It's half-way up.